# Javad Adib







### Full Stack Developer

Lives 15+ years with code and debugging as a programmer. A lover of microservice architecture due to the freedom of technology and scalability. Collaboration with dozens of specialists and teamwork led to the acquisition of valuable insight, particularly on e-commerce. Built infrastructures of over 7 multi-million dollar projects from scratch. The learner who knows how to learn. Open-source enthusiast.

🔀 mr.javad.adib@gmail.com





06/2022 v7.9.0

## **Professional Experience**

#### Founder, CEO, and Full Stack Developer

**Jibres** 

(2 years 7 months) 12/2019 - present

- Implemented an integrated cloud eCommerce solution for 1,000+ businesses containing website, app, PoS software, CRM, CMS, accounting software, ticketing system, and form builder.
- Joined the bug bounty program and introduced the new WAF that filters and monitors 99% of the attacks.
- Launched an automated app factory that generated the native android shopping app without coding in less than 10 minutes.

#### **Full Stack Team Lead**

Ermile

(4 years 7 months) 06/2015 - 12/2019

- Spearheaded the 15 members' cross-functional team, and launched a product that earned about 1M users in just a month.
- Constructed an educational management system that serves four organizations, 500,000+ students, and 2,000+ teachers.
- Built Siftal UI framework, Dash as PHP framework with MVC pattern, 2x the development speed by consolidated SPA.

#### Computer Lecturer

Teacher

(12 years 10 months) 06/2006 - 04/2019

- Taught 2,000+ students in web technologies courses, ICDL in 4 universities, vocational colleges, and private classes.
- Created and published tens of hours of unique free web and office video tutorials, which has led to an acquisition of skills by thousands of Persian speakers from around the world.

#### Web UI/UX Designer

Freelancer

(6 years 10 months) 09/2008 - 06/2015

- Designed and developed 40+ WordPress websites with HTML5 and CSS3, user experience, and communicated with dozens of customers, including universities, companies, and celebrities.
- Strengthened negotiation skills, mastered sales skills, optimized speed of 10+ websites, achieved high SEO rank.

### Volunteer work

#### **DevOps and Frontend Developer**

Khadije Charity

(4 years 6 months) 12/2017 - 05/2022

 Developed the website and all the software infrastructure to accelerate and fulfilled the wishes of 110,000+ people.

#### **Software Solutions for Business - Expert**

WorldSkills

(5 years 3 months) 06/2010 - 08/2015

 Tutored and trained three talents who have won medals in national competitions; held the national team camp to attend WorldSkills Sao Paulo 2015.

### Education

#### M.S. in Information Technology Management

Azad University 2015 - 2022

### B.S. in Computer Software Engineering

Azad University

2008 - 2014

### **Skills**

Fully Proficient Web Technology HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP Language C, C++, C#, VB.NET, Node.js, TypeScript, Bash, Python Data Structure and Database MySQL, SQL Server, JSON, YAML Web Service SOAP, REST API, GraphQL

Back-end PHP Web Framework Laravel, Symfony

Front-end JS Library Vanilla JS, jQuery, Alpine.js, React, Vue.js

CSS Framework Tailwind, Bootstrap, Semantic UI, Materialize

Build Tool Sass, Grunt, Gulp, Gradle, Webpack

Version Control System Git, Github, Gitlab

Test Driven Development - TDD PHPUnit

CI/CD Container Docker, Kubernetes

Backend Web Server Nginx, Apache

Server Configuration Framework UI cPanel, DirectAdmin
Network DNS, DHCP, HTTP, SSL, TLS, SMTP, FTP, MIME, SSH
OS Windows, Ubuntu, Debian, CentOS, macOS, VMware ESXi
Software Development Methodology Scrum, Agile, Kanban
Microsoft Office Specialist Excel, Access, PowerPoint, VBA

**Graphic Design Tool** Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Figma **Miscellaneous** Cloud Development, SaaS, Database Design, QA, Algorithm, Object Orientated, A/B Testing, OWASP, CORS, XML, XHTML, Twig, AJAX, PWA, SCSS, NPM, Composer, LEMP, LAMP, CLI, Wireguard, Accounting, Maintenance, VoIP, Crwal, SEO, S3, Analysis, RDBMS, OOD, SOLID, Marketing, Teamwork, AWS

### Awards and Honors

#### **Membership**

Iran's National Elites Foundation 2013

#### Silver Medal

WorldSkills Iran - IT Software Solutions for Business 2009

#### Medallion for Excellence

WorldSkills Iran - IT Software Applications 2008